The biggest names in the 2026 NFL draft
have descended on Indianapolis. Now the
real fun begins. Have you ever wondered
what the schedule is like for the 319
NFL prospects attending the combine?
Let's get into it.
The players are broken up into nine
groups by position and operate off a
staggered schedule. That means everyone
has the same itinerary over a 5-day
span, but they start on different days.
The Dline, linebackers, and specialists
kick off the week on Monday, and the O
line closes out the combine on Sunday.
The first two days of a player's week
are filled with orientation and medical
exams, which can be the most crucial
part of the week for players coming off
a major injury or players with an
extensive injury history.
The next day includes the first public
facing event of the week for players,
the media interviews.
What's up?
>> Good morning. How y'all doing?
>> This is a great opportunity for players
to show off their personality to the
public and maybe even win over a few
fans.
>> Whatever team end up picking me, going
to get the best out of me, going to get
the best player in the drive.
>> New ways to get open, getting more
creative,
>> just soaking everything and I'm just
excited about everything. So, it's been
fun so far.
As all of this is happening, players are
also spending a few hours each day doing
their most important task of the week,
which is meeting with the 32 NFL teams.
These closed dooror sessions are vital
for coaches, scouts, and general
managers to get to know the prospects as
a person. It's also a great opportunity
for players to show off their football
knowledge by drawing up plays and
schemes on the whiteboard.
>> Welcome to Indie. This is the NFL
scouting combine.
>> The part of the combine that draws the
most attention is the onfield workouts,
which are televised live for hours each
day.
These workouts consist of speed,
agility, and explosive tests such as the
high jump, broad jump, 40-yard dash, and
three cone. Not to mention the specific
football drills.
>> I mean, this is so smooth.
There you go.
>> He's flying.
>> Wow. Look at that.
>> He's got quick feet. Bailey. Goodness
gracious.
>> Talk about guys being able to drop their
weight and change direction.
>> All right, here we go.
>> Look at this dude move.
>> And he was just raving about how the
depth of this group.
>> He has got an elite elite get off as a
rusher. We'll see how it translates
here. These workouts can be a useful
data point for front offices because it
places all participating players in the
same controlled environment which can be
beneficial to make direct comparison.
>> He's got exceptional ball skills. He'll
be great going through that.
>> Blown away by the 40 times.
>> Nice. And he's got excellent feet. Ball
does come out nice.
>> Holy safety is right.
>> He was absolutely flying. That ties the
record of Vernon Davis and Doran
Dickerson.
>> Oh guys,
>> nice. That was a great rep.
>> After wrapping up their onfield
workouts, the players return to Lucas
Oil Stadium one last time the following
day where they show off their strength
in the bench press.
Finally, after their weekl long job
interview is complete, the players leave
Indianapolis to go prep for the next
stage of the pre-draft process.